<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on zqw's notes</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/categories/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on zqw's notes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://uzqw.github.io/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Custom Linux Distro: From Yocto Build to 60% Boot Time Optimization</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/230615-linux-boot-optimization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/230615-linux-boot-optimization/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A key user experience metric for NAS products: how long from pressing power to accessing shared folders? Our target was 30 seconds, but the original took 75 seconds. This post documents the complete journey from 75s to 30s.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>NAS Disk Health Monitoring: From smartctl to Custom Agent</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/220815-disk-health-agent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/220815-disk-health-agent/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A NAS&amp;rsquo;s most important job is protecting user data. Disk failures often have warning signs, and SMART technology can detect problems early. This post documents how to build a disk health monitoring agent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Compiling Nginx from Source: Understanding Module Architecture and Custom Extensions</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/211207-compile-nginx-fdfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 21:56:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/211207-compile-nginx-fdfs/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Most people install Nginx via package managers, but compiling from source truly reveals its module mechanism. This post uses FastDFS module integration as an example to analyze Nginx&amp;rsquo;s build system and modular architecture.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building a Mini Filesystem: Custom FS with FUSE + Go</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/210810-fuse-filesystem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/210810-fuse-filesystem/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The best way to learn filesystems is to write one yourself. This post uses FUSE + Go to implement an in-memory filesystem with basic read/write operations, deep-diving into core concepts like inode and block.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Linux Boot Process: Complete Guide from Power Button to Login</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/210520-linux-boot-process/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/210520-linux-boot-process/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;To be a solid systems engineer, you need to deeply understand the Linux boot process. Only by knowing &amp;ldquo;what normal looks like&amp;rdquo; can you quickly troubleshoot when things go wrong. This post walks through every stage from power button to login screen.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hugo Blog CI/CD: GitHub Actions Auto-Build and Multi-Environment Deployment</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/210321-hugo-auto-deployment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/210321-hugo-auto-deployment/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;From the early days of &lt;code&gt;hugo &amp;amp;&amp;amp; scp&lt;/code&gt; to Git Push-triggered auto-deployment — this post documents the evolution of my Hugo blog CI/CD setup, along with production-grade GitHub Actions best practices.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Linux Desktop Customization: Flatpak Theme Integration and Container Isolation Principles</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/210126-flatpak-theme/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 21:56:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/210126-flatpak-theme/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A simple requirement: make a Flatpak-installed PDF reader support dark mode. But solving it involves Flatpak&amp;rsquo;s sandbox mechanism, filesystem mounts, and environment variable injection — concepts highly similar to Docker/K8s containerization.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>