<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Distributed Systems on zqw's notes</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/categories/distributed-systems/</link><description>Recent content in Distributed Systems on zqw's notes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://uzqw.github.io/categories/distributed-systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Temporal Single-Node Reliability Deep Dive: How It Survives Server Crashes, Network Failures, and Rollback Errors</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/260213-temporal-reliability/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/260213-temporal-reliability/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Writing business logic with Temporal is pure joy — &amp;ldquo;code like a single-machine program, get distributed fault tolerance for free.&amp;rdquo; But after the honeymoon phase, a nagging question remains: &lt;strong&gt;Is it really reliable?&lt;/strong&gt; What if the Server crashes? What about network partitions? What if the rollback itself fails? This article tears apart these questions from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dive into K8s 02: Cilium Replaces Flannel — Goodbye VXLAN Tax, Hello eBPF Native Networking</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/251210-dive-into-k8s-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:38:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/251210-dive-into-k8s-02/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Last post, we hand-rolled Flannel in Kind cluster and witnessed the 50-byte per-packet VXLAN encapsulation overhead via tcpdump. This time, we replace Flannel with Cilium, leveraging eBPF to completely eliminate this &amp;ldquo;network tax&amp;rdquo;, and use Hubble for traffic visualization.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dive into K8s: Hand-Rolling CNI with Kind, From CrashLoop to VXLAN Packet Capture</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/251207-dive-into-k8s-01/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 17:38:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/251207-dive-into-k8s-01/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend, I built a &amp;ldquo;networkless&amp;rdquo; cluster from scratch on Manjaro using &lt;code&gt;kind&lt;/code&gt;, manually debugged missing kernel modules and CNI plugins, and finally witnessed the VXLAN encapsulation process with &lt;code&gt;tcpdump&lt;/code&gt;. This post documents the entire journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Temporal vs K8s Controller: Declarative vs Imperative Control Plane Paradigms</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/250715-temporal-vs-k8s-controller/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/250715-temporal-vs-k8s-controller/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;K8s Controllers and Temporal are both &amp;ldquo;control plane&amp;rdquo; technologies, but they represent fundamentally different design philosophies. This post deep-dives into their core differences and explores how to combine them in AI Infra platforms.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Temporal in Practice: From Saga Pattern to Self-Healing Distributed Transactions</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/250710-temporal-saga/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/250710-temporal-saga/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While building a trading system backend, I used Temporal to solve the classic distributed transaction consistency problem. This post breaks down Temporal&amp;rsquo;s core mechanisms and explores its applications in AI task scheduling.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Postmortem: Debugging a Zookeeper Split-Brain in Production</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/211014-kafka-cluester/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 21:56:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/211014-kafka-cluester/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;One night at 2 AM, Kafka message lag alerts fired. Investigation revealed a Zookeeper cluster split-brain — two nodes both thought they were the Leader. This post documents the full debugging and recovery process.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Go Microservices War Stories: 5 Lessons from Dependency Management to Service Discovery</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/210922-go-feature/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 21:56:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/210922-go-feature/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Microservices isn&amp;rsquo;t just about splitting up a monolith. This post documents 5 real pitfalls I hit in Go microservices projects, and how to avoid them.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>