<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Temporal on zqw's notes</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/tags/temporal/</link><description>Recent content in Temporal on zqw's notes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://uzqw.github.io/tags/temporal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Temporal Single-Node Reliability Deep Dive: How It Survives Server Crashes, Network Failures, and Rollback Errors</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/260213-temporal-reliability/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/260213-temporal-reliability/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Writing business logic with Temporal is pure joy — &amp;ldquo;code like a single-machine program, get distributed fault tolerance for free.&amp;rdquo; But after the honeymoon phase, a nagging question remains: &lt;strong&gt;Is it really reliable?&lt;/strong&gt; What if the Server crashes? What about network partitions? What if the rollback itself fails? This article tears apart these questions from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Temporal vs K8s Controller: Declarative vs Imperative Control Plane Paradigms</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/250715-temporal-vs-k8s-controller/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/250715-temporal-vs-k8s-controller/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;K8s Controllers and Temporal are both &amp;ldquo;control plane&amp;rdquo; technologies, but they represent fundamentally different design philosophies. This post deep-dives into their core differences and explores how to combine them in AI Infra platforms.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Temporal in Practice: From Saga Pattern to Self-Healing Distributed Transactions</title><link>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/250710-temporal-saga/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://uzqw.github.io/posts/250710-temporal-saga/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While building a trading system backend, I used Temporal to solve the classic distributed transaction consistency problem. This post breaks down Temporal&amp;rsquo;s core mechanisms and explores its applications in AI task scheduling.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>